[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "type": "multiple",
    "question": "Select the three main advantages of packet-switched networks!",
    "options": [
      "Efficient resource management",
      "Simple implementation",
      "Predictable performance with guarantees",
      "Good fault tolerance",
      "Low performance in case of bursty traffic or short data flows",
      "Complex circuit establishment and tear-down phases"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [0, 1, 3]
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "type": "single",
    "question": "Which layer of ISO/OSI is responsible for media access control?",
    "options": [
      "L4-Transport",
      "L2-Data link",
      "L7-Application",
      "L5-Session",
      "L1-Physical",
      "L3-Network",
      "L6-Presentation"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [1]
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "type": "multiple",
    "question": "Which statements are true for the baseband transmission?",
    "options": [
      "The signal is transmitted in a wide band of the frequency range instead of the entire range.",
      "The signal is tranmitted using the entire frequency range.",
      "The signal is encoded into a carrier wave by a technique called modulation.",
      "The digital signal is directly converted into current or voltage."
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [1, 3]
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "type": "multiple",
    "question": "Which statements are true for the simplex stop-and-wait protocol (noisy channel)?",
    "options": [
      "It requires a full duplex channel.",
      "It contnously sends packets using the pipeline technique.",
      "Lost acnkowledgments result in duplicate packet reception at the reciever side.",
      "In case of packet loss, the lost packet is retransmitted after a timeout period. The timeout is managed by a timer."
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [2, 3]
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "type": "single",
    "question": "What does the property called \"carrier sensing\" mean?",
    "options": [
      "The station can sense the error of the carrier wave.",
      "The stations can check the state of the physical media before data tranmission. The channel could be idle or busy.",
      "The stations get information about the channel state from a central server or entity.",
      "The channel state can be determined with a modified carrier wave. The wave is modified by modulation."
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [1]
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "type": "multiple",
    "question": "Which statements are true?",
    "options": [
      "CSMA/CD is not needed in switches.",
      "Every bridge is a switch.",
      "Each port of a switch can only be connected to an end-host or another switch.",
      "End-hosts are connected to switches with full duplex links.",
      "CSMA/CD is not needed in bridges."
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [0, 3]
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "type": "single",
    "question": "Which IPv4 address class results in the smallest number of IP blocks? With other terms: which address class can be used in the smallest number of networks? How many entities can own an IP range from a given class, where is this number the smallest?",
    "options": [
      "Class C",
      "Class B",
      "The number is the same in each class",
      "Class A"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [3]
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "type": "multiple",
    "question": "Select the three key components of computer networks!",
    "options": [
      "CPU",
      "copper cable",
      "end-hosts",
      "fluxus condensator",
      "hoax cable",
      "monitor",
      "links",
      "switches/Routers"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [2, 6, 7]
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "type": "multiple",
    "question": "What additional services are implemented by TCP (in addition to IP)?",
    "options": [
      "Non-reliable data transport, but it ensures in-order delivery.",
      "Connection oriented services.",
      "Reliable data transport with in-order delivery.",
      "Connection-less datagram service."
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [1, 2]
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "type": "multiple",
    "question": "Which statements are true for alternating bit protocol (ABP)?",
    "options": [
      "It requires a full duplex channel.",
      "Packets carry a sequence number which is either 0 or 1.",
      "Lost acknowledgments result in duplicate packet reception at the receiver side.",
      "The sequence number enables the receiver to recognize duplicate packets."
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [1, 2, 3]
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "type": "multiple",
    "question": "Which statements are true for broadband transmission?",
    "options": [
      "The signal is transmitted in a wide band of the frequency range instead of the entire range",
      "The signal is transmitted using the entire frequency range.",
      "The digital signal is directly converted into current or voltage.",
      "The signal is encoded into a carrier wave by a technique called modulation."
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [0, 3]
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "type": "multiple",
    "question": "Select the three main disadvantages of circuit-switched networks!",
    "options": [
      "Buffer-management is needed",
      "Unpredictable performance",
      "New circuit is needed in case of failure",
      "Complex circuit establishment and tear-down phases",
      "Low performance in case of bursty traffic or short data flows",
      "Congestion control is needed"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [2, 3, 4]
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "type": "multiple",
    "question": "Which statements are true for the sliding window protocol?",
    "options": [
      "Lost acknowledgments result in duplicate packet reception at the receiver side.",
      "It requires a full duplex channel. Data and acknowledgment packets can travel simultaneously.",
      "Frames with sequence numbers that are not in the receiving window are ignored by the receiver. Acks are also sent for these packets.",
      "Acknowledgements and the ack numbers are used to enable the sender to transmit more data (e.g., the next frame)."
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [1, 2, 3]
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "type": "truefalse",
    "question": "TCP is very efficient for transmitting web traffic, since it can almost fully utilize the available bandwidth in the network.",
    "correctAnswer": true
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "type": "truefalse",
    "question": "Packet loss can only be cause by network congestion, so it is a clear evidence of network congestion?",
    "correctAnswer": false
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "type": "truefalse",
    "question": "Using its \"Cubic function,\" TCP CUBIC can ramp up its sending rate faster than the slow start mechanism.",
    "correctAnswer": true
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "type": "truefalse",
    "question": "Packet loss can only be caused by network congestion, so it is clear evidence of network congestion.",
    "correctAnswer": false
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "type": "single",
    "question": "What does the reception of three duplicate acknowledgements mean in TCP Reno?",
    "options": [
      "It is like a single acknowledgement.",
      "Packet loss",
      "Good transmission.",
      "Sliding the window by 3 segments."
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [1]
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "type": "single",
    "question": "Which statement is true for pure ALOHA?",
    "options": [
      "If there is data to be sent, it sends the data. The data is transmitted immediately.",
      "When the data is ready for transmission, the frame will be sent at the boundary of the next time slot.",
      "Before transmission, the station checks the physical media. If it is idle, it sends the data with probability p and waits for the next slot with probability 1-p.",
      "Before transmission, the station checks the physical media. If it is idle, it sends the data."
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [0]
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "type": "single",
    "question": "Select the IPv4 address class where the largest number of hosts can be defined?",
    "options": [
      "Class B",
      "Class A",
      "The same number of hosts can be defined in each class.",
      "Class C"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [1]
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "type": "single",
    "question": "Which layer of ISO/OSI does contain TCP?",
    "options": [
      "L5-Session",
      "L6-Presentation",
      "L1-Physical",
      "L3-Network",
      "L4-Transport",
      "L7-Application",
      "L2-Data link"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [4]
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "type": "single",
    "question": "Which statement is true for the Physical layer?",
    "options": [
      "Transferring messages between two applications",
      "All the data is transmitted via radio waves",
      "Applying error correction to handle channel noise",
      "Transferring information (bits) between two physically interconnected devices"
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [3]
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "type": "single",
    "question": "What is true for Spanning Tree Protocol (STP) used by bridges?",
    "options": [
      "The root of the spanning tree is the bridge with the smallest bridge ID.",
      "A centralized algorithm calculates the tree and reconfigures the bridges accordingly.",
      "It enables loops in the topology if the performance can be increased this way.",
      "In case of unknown destination, we send the frame to all the neighbors and wait for replies."
    ],
    "correctAnswers": [0]
  },
  {
    "id": 24,
    "type": "numeric",
    "question": "There is a code S whose Hamming-distance d(S)=2. How many simple bit-errors can we detect with the use of code S?",
    "correctAnswer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 25,
    "type": "numeric",
    "question": "There is a code S whose Hamming-distance d(S)=15. How many simple bit-errors can we detect with the use of code S?",
    "correctAnswer": 14
  }
]
